When it comes to murder, seduction and betrayal, he
wrote the book. Now he's living it.
The Singing Detective is a comedy, music, mystery film directed by Keith Gordon.
Tormented and bedridden by a debilitating disease, a mystery writer relives his
detective stories through his imagination and hallucinations.
Dan Dark, played by Robert Downey Jr..
Nicola / Nina / Blonde, played by Robin Wright.
Dr. Gibbon, played by Mel Gibson.
Mark Binney, played by Jeremy Northam.
Nurse Mills, played by Katie Holmes.
First Hood, played by Adrien Brody.
The Singing Detective is a 2003 American musical crime comedy film directed by Keith Gordon and
loosely based on the BBC serial of the same name, a work by British writer Dennis Potter.
It stars Robert Downey Jr.
and features a supporting cast that includes Katie Holmes, Adrien Brody, Robin Wright, Mel
Gibson, Jeremy Northam and Carla Gugino as well as a number of songs from the 1950s.
The film explores themes of adultery, infidelity,
paranoia, hallucination, musical.
The tone is lighthearted and dark and mind_bending.